lightspeedsystems.com 2019-05-15

# Privacy Policy - Lightspeed Systems, Inc.

**Lightspeed Systems’ Commitment to Your Privacy**

Your privacy is critically important to Lightspeed Systems, Inc. We have developed this Privacy Policy to outline how we collect, use, disclose, transfer, and store your information. Lightspeed Systems, Inc. is fully committed to the security and protection of your privacy.

Lightspeed Systems, Inc. provides a variety of services (“Services”) to securely manage technology users, Internet-enabled devices, and Internet access. We understand the importance of privacy to our online visitors, to schools who register for our Services, (“Schools”) and to students and staff (“end users”) whose information we may access on behalf of a School.

  1. We will always be transparent in the data we collect and how it is used.
  2. We will only collect the data that is necessary for the solutions and functions that the school has purchased/contracted.
  3. We will always treat that data with the utmost security and privacy.
  4. We will never sell student personal information; we will never share it without the software license holders written authorization, and we will never use it to attempt to sell advertising to students.

As described below, Schools decide which data is integrated with our Services.

This privacy policy applies to our websites and Services (lightspeedsystems.com, lsaccess.me, lsurl.me, lsfilter.com, lsmdm.com, lsoverride.me, and relay.school) and describes the steps we take to protect your data. It details the termssurrounding our use of the personally identifiable information we collect, namely our information gathering, use, maintenance, and dissemination practices necessary for the Services. Click on the links below to jump to each section:

  1. [Your Data: How We Collect and Use Information](https://www.lightspeedsystems.com/privacy/#section-1)
  2. [Student Safety](https://www.lightspeedsystems.com/privacy/#section-2)
  3. [Third Parties: How We May Share Your Data](https://www.lightspeedsystems.com/privacy/#section-3)
  4. [Choice: Your Options Regarding Your Data](https://www.lightspeedsystems.com/privacy/#section-4)
  5. [Security: How We Store and Protect Your Information](https://www.lightspeedsystems.com/privacy/#section-5)
  6. [European Union Data Protection](https://www.lightspeedsystems.com/privacy/#section-6)
  7. [Changes: How Changes to Our Privacy Policy Will Be Communicated](https://www.lightspeedsystems.com/privacy/#section-7)
  8. [How to Contact Lightspeed Systems](https://www.lightspeedsystems.com/privacy/#section-8)

As you are navigating between school and related sites, please be aware that other parties’ privacy policies may come into play. If you are using any of the Services through an educational or other institution that is a customer of Lightspeed Systems, Inc. this policy does not supersede the terms of any agreements between Lightspeed Systems, Inc. and any other party, nor does it affect the terms of any agreement between any user of the Services and their employer, their educational institution, or any third party. Please make sure that you read the terms of any privacy policies that you enter into with parties’ other than Lightspeed Systems, Inc. including your employer or educational institution, as those policies may also explain how your personal information is used by those parties. If you are accessing Lightspeed Systems, Inc. through a third-party, public, or unsecured internet provider, please be advised that any information you disclose or publish during the course of such access may be collected by any such provider and that Lightspeed Systems, Inc. has no control and makes no representation as to the possible use of this information by any such provider.

  1. **YOUR DATA: How we collect and use information**

We collect the following types of information.

**Information about Schools:** When a School administrator registers a School with Lightspeed Systems, Inc. or corresponds with us online, we ask for certain information including a contact name, school name, school district, school email address and/or account name, phone number, message content, and information relating to the School’s information systems. We may also retain information provided by a School if the School sends us a message, posts content to our website or through our Service, or responds to emails or surveys. Once a School begins using a Lightspeed Systems, Inc. Service, we will keep records of activities related to the Service. We use this information to operate, maintain, and provide the features and functionality of the Service. Including customer service, support, and billing; to analyze our Service offerings and functionality; to communicate with our Schools and website visitors; to exchange information, and to offer related services such as user group membership and event registration.

**Student Data:** Lightspeed Systems, Inc. may have access to personally identifiable information about students (“Student Data”) in the course of providing its Services to a School. We recognize Student Data is confidential and do not use such data for any purpose other than to provide the Services on the School’s behalf. In most instances, Lightspeed Systems, Inc. receives Student Data only from the School and never interacts with the Student directly. In some instances, depending on the type of Service used by the School, the Schools may allow Students to interact with a Lightspeed Systems, Inc. Service. In that instance, the School provides each student with login credentials and confirms that it has obtained appropriate parental consents, as needed before the student is permitted to access the Service. Lightspeed Systems, Inc. has access to Student Data only as requested by the School and only for the purposes of performing Services on the School’s behalf.

We may collect the following types of personally identifiable information directly from children: first name, last name, email address, password, IP address, grade level, and school. We may also generate a login ID for the child that is different than the child’s actual name or under the School’s direction, collect login/authentication data via a student information system identification number or other system designated by Customer.

Parents should consult the school’s Acceptable/Responsible Use, Social Media, Personnel, and Instructional Policies for more information about the school’s policies and practices for protecting children on the Internet. Teachers are reminded to also be aware of their obligations under the Ethical Standards for educators in their state and to be conscious of their role as a model for students while interacting with students using Lightspeed Systems, Inc. Services.

See “Student Safety” below for further explanation of our commitment to online student safety.

**Non-Personally Identifiable Information:** We may collect certain non-personally identifiable information from visitors to our sites and users of our Services, such as the date and time of their visit, the type of browser used (e.g., Chrome, Firefox, Internet Explorer), the type of operating system used (e.g., Windows 7 or Mac OS), the ISP from which the visitor receives Internet access, and aggregate information regarding what pages users of the site access or visit. We may collect data for Schools to monitor and generate reports of their users’ online search queries, websites visited or blocked from visiting recorded web activity, and device geolocation for purpose of asset recovery. In addition, we may monitor Schools’ onboarding tasks completed, search queries on our sites, number of users’ sessions on our websites, city and state/province where last accessing our Services, responses to our survey questions, and content provided on managed devices via customizable fields.

We may also match non-personally identifiable information from registered members with personally identifiable information (such as the member’s name) in our database to track deployment progress, troubleshoot Services issues, analyze usage, and otherwise monitor Services to make improvements.

Lightspeed Systems, Inc. and its third-party service providers use cookies (both session and persistent cookies) and other tracking mechanisms to automatically collect information including IP addresses, session sources, and other data which tracks users’ access to the Services. We may combine this information with other personal information we collect from you (and our third-party service providers may do so on our behalf).

**Employment Applications:** In connection with a job application or inquiry, we may collect data about you, including your educational background, résumé or curriculum vitae, and other information, including your ethnicity or criminal background information where required or permitted by law. We may use this information throughout Lightspeed Systems for the purpose of employment consideration. We will keep the information for future consideration unless you direct us not to do so.

**Cookie Policy**

**Clear GIFs, pixel tags, and other technologies:** Clear GIFs (also known as web beacons, web bugs or pixel tags) are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies. In contrast to cookies, which are stored on your computer’s hard drive, clear GIFs are embedded invisibly on web pages. We may use clear GIFs, in connection with Lightspeed Systems, Inc. Services to, among other things, track the activities of visitors, help us manage content, and compile statistics about site usage. We and our third-party service providers also use clear GIFs in HTML emails to our customers to help us track e-mail response rates, identify when our e-mails are viewed, and track whether our e-mails are forwarded.

We use or may use the data collected through cookies, log files, device identifiers, and clear GIFs to (a) remember information so in subsequent visits a user will not have to re-enter it; (b) provide custom, personalized content, and information; (c) monitor the effectiveness of our Services; (d) monitor aggregate metrics such as total number of visitors, traffic, and usage on our website and our Services; (e) diagnose or fix technology problems; and (f) help users efficiently access information after signing in.

**Third-Party Analytics:** We use automated devices, applications, and other means, such as Google Analytics, to evaluate usage of our Lightspeed Systems, Inc. web sites and Services. We use these tools to help us improve our Services, performance and user experiences. These entities may use cookies and other tracking technologies to perform their services. Third-party advertising networks are never allowed to collect information about the users of our websites or Services.

**Do-Not-Track:** Currently, our systems do not recognize browser “do-not-track” requests. You may, however, disable certain tracking as discussed in this section (e.g., by disabling cookies).

**Data Controller** : By providing Lightspeed Systems, Inc. information via our website, Tradeshow, Lightspeed event, Partner event, e-mails, phone calls, chat or support cases, and maintained in our systems, you authorize Lightspeed Systems, Inc. to serve as the Data Controller.

**Data Processor** : By licensing to use Lightspeed Systems, Inc. services, you authorize Lightspeed Systems, Inc. to serve as the Data Processor for the licensed services.

  2. **STUDENT SAFETY**

Lightspeed Systems, Inc. complies with the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA, see [www.ftc.gov/privacy/coppafaqs.shtm](http://www.ftc.gov/privacy/coppafaqs.shtm)) and the Student Privacy Pledge ([studentprivacypledge.org](http://studentprivacypledge.org/)) to ensure the online safety of children. Student accounts are provided only through a verified educator, school, or educational organization. Educators should obtain parental permission before issuing accounts to students.

We meet the following guidelines listed below and agree to:

  * NOT collect online contact information without the consent of either a parent or a qualified educator or educational institution.
  * NOT collect personally identifiable offline contact information.
  * NOT distribute to third parties any personally identifiable information without prior parental consent.
  * NOT entice by the prospect of a special game, prize, or other activity or to divulge more information than is needed to participate in the activity.
  * NOT use or disclose student information for behavioral targeting of advertisements to students.
  * NOT build a personal profile of a student other than for supporting authorized educational/school purposes.

  3. **THIRD PARTIES: How we may share your information**

Personal information is only shared in a few limited circumstances as described below. Lightspeed Systems, Inc. will not give, sell, rent, loan, or otherwise disclose to any third parties outside of Lightspeed Systems, Inc and its agents, except when we have your permission or as required:

  * With those that provide us with technology services (e.g. web hosting and analytics services), but only with entities with comparably strict privacy policies and strictly for the purpose of carrying out their work for us.
  * Under special circumstances, such as when we believe in good faith that disclosure is reasonably necessary to (i) comply with a lawful request by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements, (ii) enforce the [Terms of Use](https://www.lightspeedsystems.com/tc), (iii) respond to claims that any content provided by using the Services violates the rights of third parties, or (iv) protect the rights, property, or personal safety of Lightspeed Systems, Inc., its users, or the public

Aggregated personal information is used to determine the demographic composition of our user base and to distribute statistics and general marketplace information about Lightspeed Systems, Inc. We may disclose aggregated user statistics to describe the Services to prospective partners and other third parties and for other lawful purposes. This aggregated information does not identify specific users.

We do not use personal information for any other commercial purpose.

Further, Lightspeed Systems, Inc. recognizes its potential liability when onward transferring EU individuals’ data received pursuant to the EU-US Privacy Shield.  An individual has the ability, under certain conditions, to invoke binding arbitration for complaints regarding Privacy Shield compliance not resolved by any of the other Privacy Shield mechanisms.  Please refer to [Annex I](https://www.privacyshield.gov/article?id=ANNEX-I-introduction) of the Privacy Shield for additional information.

In certain areas of the Services, Lightspeed Systems, Inc. makes announcements, email, chat, polls, forums, discussions, and/or news groups available. Please remember that any information that is disclosed in these areas becomes public information, and you should exercise caution when deciding to disclose any of your personal or other information in these or any other publicly available site. And if you see inappropriate content posted by any other user, please report that information to us so we can review the post and respond accordingly.

  4. **CHOICE: Your Options Regarding Your Data**

**For Data, we collect via our products:**

**Account information and settings:** Adult users of Lightspeed Systems, Inc. Services have a right to access the data collected and used by Lightspeed Systems, Inc. Schools may access and update account information and modify Services by signing into an administrator account. Adult users may access and change the information collected during account creation at any time and as often as necessary by choosing the “edit account information” option or other similar functionality offered in the Services. To access or change your personal information, log into your account through the Services. For data, not available through such an account, please contact us via the contact information below. Users and visitors may opt out of receiving future promotional electronic mailings from Lightspeed Systems, Inc. by following the unsubscribe procedures indicated in the mailing.  Adult users of Lightspeed Systems, Inc. Services should contact their educational institution or other organization providing the Service about access requests to be forgotten, electronic copies of data, requests for data deletion, and/or data depersonalization.

**Student data:** Student users of Lightspeed Systems, Inc. Services and their parents should contact their educational institution or other organization providing the Service about access to the personal information collected by that institution including requests to be forgotten, requests for data, requests for data deletion, and/or data depersonalization.

**Deleting or disabling cookies:** Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but if you prefer, you can edit your browser options to block them in the future. The Help portion of the toolbar on most browsers will tell you how to prevent your computer from accepting new cookies, how to have the browser notify you when you receive a new cookie, or how to disable cookies altogether. Users of Lightspeed Systems, Inc. services who disable cookies will be able to browse certain areas of our sites, but some features may not function.

**User-data retention:** Following termination or deactivation of a School account, Lightspeed Systems, Inc. may retain profile information and content for a commercially reasonable time for backup, archival, or audit purposes, but all Student Data associated with the School will be deleted in accordance with Lightspeed Systems, Inc. Data Deletion policy, or in accordance with active DPA, DSA or SLA, or within 90 days. We may maintain anonymized or aggregated data, including usage data, for analytics purposes. If you have any questions about data retention or deletion, please contact us via the contact information below

Data Portability: License holders of Lightspeed Systems, Inc. products may request in writing that the data they provided be returned to them in electronic format. Within a reasonable time Lightspeed Systems, Inc. will return the data provided by the license holder for the products they have licensed.

Individuals who provided information via our websites, Tradeshow, Lightspeed event, Partner event, e-mail or phone call may request in writing that the data they provided be returned to them in electronic format. Within a reasonable time Lightspeed Systems, Inc. will return the data provided.

**For Data, we collect from visitors of our websites:**

**Account information and settings** : Adult users and visitors of the Lightspeed Systems, Inc. website have a right to access the data collected and used by Lightspeed Systems, Inc. To make requests to access or change account information, be forgotten, electronic copies of data, data deletion, and/or data depersonalization, please contact us via the contact information below. Users and visitors may opt out of receiving future promotional electronic mailings from Lightspeed Systems, Inc. by following the unsubscribe procedures indicated in the mailing.

**Children’s data** : Lightspeed Systems, Inc. does not knowingly solicit or attempt to collect information from children via its websites. We ask that anyone under the age of 13 not use our websites or submit information to us. Please contact us via the contact information below if you have any questions, concerns, need to access, change, or delete the Personal Information that has been submitted by a child.

**User-data retention** : Lightspeed Systems, Inc. may retain profile information and content for a commercially reasonable time. We may maintain anonymized or aggregated data, including usage data, for analytics purposes. If you have any questions about data retention or deletion, please contact us via the contact information below.

Please contact us at the address below if you have any other questions or concerns about the information you receive from us or the information that we collect from you.

  5. **SECURITY: How We Store and Protect Your Data**

**Storage:** All of your personal information is stored on servers at locations designed specifically to ensure that only authorized individuals have access to the server or its data. Lightspeed Systems, Inc. maintains strict administrative, technical, and physical procedures to protect information stored on our servers. Access to information is limited through login credentials to those employees who require it to perform their job functions.

**Processing:** Industry-standard Secure Socket Layer (SSL) encryption technology is used to safeguard the account registration process. Other security safeguards include but are not limited to data encryption, firewalls, two-factor authentication, and physical-access controls.

  6. **European Union Data Protection**

**Framework Compliance:** Lightspeed Systems, Inc. complies with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information transferred from the European Union and the United Kingdom, to the United States in reliance on Privacy Shield.  Lightspeed Systems, Inc. has certified to the Department of Commerce that it adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles of Notice, Choice, Accountability for Onward Transfer, Security, Data Integrity and Purpose Limitation, Access, and Recourse, Enforcement, and Liability. If there is any conflict between the terms of this privacy policy and the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern. To learn more about the Privacy Shield program, and to view our certification page, please visit [www.privacyshield.gov](http://www.privacyshield.gov/).

**Dispute Resolution:** In compliance with the EU-US Privacy Shield Principles, Lightspeed Systems, Inc. commits to resolve complaints about your privacy and our collection or use of your personal information. European Union individuals with inquiries or complaints regarding this privacy policy should first contact Lightspeed Systems, Inc. at:

Lightspeed Systems, Inc.

℅John Genter, DPO

2500 Bee Cave Road, Suite 350

Austin, TX 78746

Lightspeed Systems, Inc. has committed to refer unresolved privacy complaints under the EU-US Privacy Shield Principles to BBB EU PRIVACY SHIELD, a non-profit alternative dispute resolution provider located in the United States and operated by the Council of Better Business Bureaus. If you do not receive timely acknowledgment of your complaint, or if your complaint is not satisfactorily addressed, please visit [www.bbb.org/EU-privacy-shield/for-eu-consumers/](http://www.bbb.org/EU-privacy-shield/for-eu-consumers/)for more information and to file a complaint.

You also have a right to raise any data protection related concerns with the supervisory data protection authority in your jurisdiction.

Lightspeed Systems, Inc. is subject to the investigatory and enforcement powers of the Federal Trade Commission (FTC).

  7. **CHANGES: How Changes to Our Privacy Policy Will Be Communicated**

Lightspeed Systems, Inc. may change this Privacy Policy from time to time. If we make significant changes in the way we treat your personal information, or to the Privacy Policy, we will provide notice to our customers inside the Service, as well as via email to primary contacts, on the Community Site, and at <https://www.lightspeedsystems.com/privacy>. Please review these changes carefully. If you agree to the changes, simply continue using the product. If you object to any of the changes to the Privacy Policy, immediately notify us at the contact information below. Unless stated otherwise, our current Privacy Policy applies to all information that Lightspeed Systems, Inc. collects via our Services and products. Using Lightspeed Systems, Inc. services and products after a notice has been communicated to you or published on our Services shall constitute consent to the changed terms and practices.

  8. **How to Contact Lightspeed Systems**

If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the information that we collect from you, or the Services, please contact us at [privacy@lightspeedsystems.com](mailto:privacy@lightspeedsystems.com) or write to:

Lightspeed Systems, Inc.

℅John Genter, DPO

2500 Bee Cave Road, Suite 350

Austin, TX 78746

In the event that you are concerned about how data you have provided Lightspeed Systems, Inc. through the Services has been used, please contact us at the address listed above. Lightspeed Systems, Inc. takes all concerns about privacy and use of data very seriously and shall endeavor to reply to you within two business days to commence its investigation of your concerns.

For more information, see [Protecting Privacy, Lightspeed Systems Overview](https://community.lightspeedsystems.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/LightspeedSystems-Protecting-Privacy.pdf)

We have signed the [Student Privacy Pledge](http://studentprivacypledge.org/?page_id=45)!

_This privacy policy was last modified on March 22, 2019. Effective Date: March 29, 2019._
